So our next step is to install repo.
Repo is simply a wrapper on top of git.
This was created by Google to make the management of AOSp source code a little bit better.
So in case you don't know what git or repo is, just keep in mind that they are source code management
tools.
So these tools help us to manage the source code and track the changes of your project.
Okay.
So to download repo now let's head to source.android.com.
We need to basically execute these commands as we did earlier.
So this command will install repo from the official package available in the Linux distribution.
So in case if this doesn't work you can you could directly download repo using the curl command.
Okay.
So let's try this command first.
So this is pretty straightforward.
Let's paste it.
So now install repo.
So I have got a problem.
Unable to locate repo.
So now let's head back to SourceForge android.com.
Now let's try the second method.
So in this method we are just using the curl command.
So this basically downloads a repo um from tools from this server.
Okay.
So this curl command is basically to download something from an external server.
So let's execute this.
Now just copy this first line here.
So while installing repo I ran into a problem.
So I was not able to install repo by using this method.
The repo is not actually available in the repository for 20.0 4.2.
So version two.
Okay, so if you have an ubuntu version which is 18.0404 or prior to that, you will not have this problem.
So you should be able to install the repo.
But unfortunately in the latest ubuntu version you don't have a repo available in the ubuntu repositories.
So these these commands will not work for you if you have the latest ubuntu.
Okay.
So even in my case I was not even able to install the repo like this because I was receiving e issues
while trying to receive this particular key using GPG command.
Okay, so these two methods were actually not working for me, but I was able to find a different solution
for that, which is, uh, pretty simple.
I'll quickly show you that.
So here is the solution.
So first basically you need to simply pull repo to bin repo folder.
Okay.
Uh like this.
So if you run it for the first time it will download it.
And then after that just change the permission by using the mode command like this okay.
And then you can check um, the version and you should find the version if it is installed successfully.
Okay.
So in my case I have already installed 2.7 okay.
So this is applicable only in case if you have the latest ubuntu.
But if you have the older uh, older version of ubuntu, uh, whatever commands are mentioned in the
source.android.com should be fine.